ALI NEHME, Ph.D.

Full Stack Developer

📞 +1 438 334-1206 @ ali.nehme@biomedinfo.co 🕜 https://nehmea.github.io/portfolio-fsd/ 💡 Brossard, Canada

SUMMARY

As a junior full stack developer, I have experience building applications with a variety of languages and frameworks, including JavaScript, Java Spring Boot, React, NodeJS, Python, Django, and PHP. Besides, I have extensive data science experience and a diverse set of soft skills from 10 years of scientific research in a computational biology. I always strive to bring 100% to the work I do. I look forward to joining a creative and hard-working team where I can grow my skills while pushing projects to success. Available starting from January 2, 2023.

SELECTED PROJECTS

StudyBuddy

11/2022 - Ongoing

A school forum for exchanging ideas and solving problems together.

- ASP.NET, C#, Razor Pages, EF6, MySQL, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS
- · Role: authorization, User, Forums, Posts, Blob storage
- https://github.com/RamiChaouki/StudyBuddy

ChatApp

1 09/2022

A messaging app/forum similar to Discord with rooms and live messaging.

- · ReactJS, NodeJS, sequelize, MySQL, socket.io, HTML, CSS
- · Role: authorization, live messaging, database management, profile management
- https://github.com/nehmea/2022-WDII-chatApp

Commons

A website that can serve as a platform for people to share their possessions.

- · Java Spring Boot, JPA, MySQL, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, CSS
- · Role: project skeleton, database management, authentication and authorization
- · https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

HomingPigeon

606/2022

A commercial website for selling postcards.

- PHP, PhpMyAdmin, HTML, CSS
- · Role: products page (add to favourites & cart), product info, profile management
- https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

Bookstore Library

₩ 05/2022

A REST API that stores information on books and users, and represent them to users.

- · Java Spring Boot, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, HTML, Bootstrap
- · Role: I developed the whole API (solo project)
- · https://github.com/nehmea/JAC_FSD_WS_Bookstore

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Principal Mentor

STEM-Away

06/2020 - Ongoing ♥ USA (Remote)

• Designed workshops and oversaw educative projects in bioinformatics.

Computational Biology Consultant

Freelancing

m 09/2019 - Ongoing

· Helped private and academic teams design projects and perform analysis.

Postdoctoral Researcher in Cancer Genomics

McGill University

- · Designed a workflow to analyze spatial transcriptomics data.
- Assisted colleagues and collaborators on eight projects with bioinformatics analysis on RNA-seq, scRNA-seq, and spatial transcriptomics data.

Postdoctoral Researcher in Molecular and Computational Biology

University of Tours

- Designed a workflow for horizontal integration of transcriptomics datasets.
- · Delivered results on 12 projects using computational and bench methods.
- · Initiated a project for biomarkers discovery in AML using data science and ML.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frameworks

Java Spring	Boot	React	NodeJ	S .I	NET core
ASP.NET	WPF	Razor I	Pages	jQuer	У
Socket IO	JPA	Sequel	ize		

Frontend

JavaScript	XAML	HTML	CSS

ThymeLeaf

Backend

Java PHP Python R C# Ubunt	Java	PHP	Python	R	C#	Ubunti
----------------------------	------	-----	--------	---	----	--------

Database

MySQL MSSQL	phpMyAdmin	Sqlite
-------------	------------	--------

Hosting

AVVS ECZ AVVS RDS XAIVIP	AWS EC2	AWS RDS	XAMPP
--------------------------	---------	---------	-------

Project Management

Github Microsoft Office Trello JIR	₹A
------------------------------------	----

Data Science

Data Wrangl	ing V	isualization	Regression
Clustering	PCA	Hypothesi	s Testing
Large data (>100m da	ata points)	

SOFT SKILLS

Agile	e Time management		Teamwork
Present	ation	Self-learning	Flexiblity

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Developer (A.E.C., 1035 hours, Avg 95%)

John Abbott's College

m 01/2022 - Ongoing

Ph.D. in Bioinformatics and Pathophysiology

Claude Bernard University Lyon 1

1 02/2013 - 11/2015

TRAINING / WORKSHOPS

The Data Science Course 2022: Complete Data Science Bootcamp

Udemy, Ongoing

LANGUAGES

English, French, Arabic